<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Philosophy on eloquent</title><link>https://tneuqole.com/tags/philosophy/</link><description>Recent content in Philosophy on eloquent</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tneuqole.com/tags/philosophy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Seneca Letter 7</title><link>https://tneuqole.com/posts/seneca_letter_7/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tneuqole.com/posts/seneca_letter_7/</guid><description>&lt;p>Humans are easily influenced. If you think yourself immune, you are either lacking self-awareness or are in denial. This is not to say that influence is inherently bad. It can be a nurturing or destructive force, depending on the source.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Take care with who and what you let enter your life. The friends we make, the media we consume, and the communities we join all create the environment of which we are the product. You must have a strong set of beliefs and principles that enable you to judge whether an influence is healthy or not. If the answer is no, ruthlessly cut it out of your life. The bad has no right to your time.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Seneca Letter 6</title><link>https://tneuqole.com/posts/seneca_letter_6/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tneuqole.com/posts/seneca_letter_6/</guid><description>&lt;p>Improving oneself is a lifelong endeavor. Do not despair at this realization, embrace it.
Your work is a noble one; you should give thanks that it will always be with you.
For it is not the destination that is significant but the journey. After all, death is the final destination for everyone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Seek a friend, or perhaps a mentor, to join you on your journey. Humans are social creatures. Much is left
unspoken, meaning much is learned by observation. There is an insight to be gained from even a novice.
Every individual is a concoction of unique experiences and perspectives. The same sight appears differently
when seen through two pairs of eyes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Seneca Letter 5</title><link>https://tneuqole.com/posts/seneca_letter_5/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tneuqole.com/posts/seneca_letter_5/</guid><description>&lt;p>Walk the middle path. The key to life lies in avoiding extremes. There is no enlightenment to be found in starvation, nor in indulgence. Do not
use philosophy as an excuse for degeneracy. Staking your happiness on worldly possessions and subjecting yourself to poverty lead to the same
destination. As Seneca says, our aim is to live in accordance with Nature. Live as a human being. Participate in society. Do not reject the world,
engage with it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Seneca Letter 4</title><link>https://tneuqole.com/posts/seneca_letter_4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tneuqole.com/posts/seneca_letter_4/</guid><description>&lt;p>Circumstances change, but human nature does not. We still act selfishly, driven by ego. We don&amp;rsquo;t
pay attention to ourselves or the present moment. We act mindlessly, all the while death approaches
indiscriminately. We worry about the future and wallow in sadness about the past. We don&amp;rsquo;t appreciate
what we have, and cry when it&amp;rsquo;s gone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What is there to be afraid of? Once death arrives, pain and fear will be no more. Why stain the
present moment with anxiety of something you have no control over? Surrender, accept, and look
within. There is peace and joy to be found in what you have right now.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>